Nasir Shadravan

Amsterdam. The Netherlands

□ (+31) 6 39 881 706 | ■ nasir@semicolon.io | • n4cr | • nasir-shadravan | • @n4cr

Summary_

I'm a Python software engineer with 15 years experience with a high interest in moving in Al. I have several years of running a software business can understand and reflect the business requirements in the technology stack efficiently. I strive to keep solutions as simple as possible to increase maintainability and reduce complexity.

Interests

Artificial Intelligence

LARGE LANGUAGE MODELS

- GPT-3
- Natural Language Processing
- Prompt Engineering
- · Generative AI
- Building AI pipelines
- Simplifying Al apps for the end users

Software Architecture Design

- Building and scaling software setup.
- Seting up automated pipeline across the software lifecycle.
- Building web apps and APIs.

Experience

DELTA Fiber (deltafiber.nl)

Schiedam, The Netherlands

Oct. 2022 - Jan 2023

PROVISIONING TEAM, PYTHON DEVELOPER

- Setup Airflow as the workflow engine for network orchestration.
- Implemented various Airflow workflows to automate network provisioning processes.
- Setup Python development guidlines within the organisation.
- Documented the developer journey to get setup within the organisation.

Xeco Labs (xecolabs.com)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Nov. 2017 - Jul 2022

CO-FOUNDER, SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Defined the scope and architecture of various client project.
- Hired and Managed external developers to help with client projects.
- Managed the development team and ensure timely delivery of the milestones.
- Managed multiple client projects from start to finish with fixed budget and timeline.
- Developed the front-end and backend of client projects mainly in Python/Django stack.
- Created internal workflow, project templates and processes within the company.

Index People Portal PYTHON, DJANGO DEVELOPER

Haarlem. The Netherlands

Nov. 2018 - Mar. 2021

• Conducted client interview and research to understand the domain and spec the requirements.

- Led a team of 3 to develop the product.
- Designed the architecture of a new client reporting dashboard and admin dashboard.
- Developed large parts of the admin and client portal of the new portal in Python/Django.
- Implemented and executed the migration of customer data from old LAMP stack to the newly built system.
- Developed a bi-directional connection between Salesforce and the portal.
- Autmoated a large numebr of processes within the organisation to free up human resources.

Coinograph (coinograph.io)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Nov. 2017 - 2022

• Developed a uniform crypto API across serval crypto exchanges using Python Django, InfluxDB.

- Generated a revenue of \$30K.
- Created a distributed data collection service to avoid rate limits from the exchanges.
- Processed and stored billions of real-time market data points in InfluxDB.
- Autmoated the provisioning and deployment of services using Ansible.
- Set up CI/CD using Jenkins.

CREATOR

OAKK Capital Partners ABN AMRO API Integration

PYTHON, DJANGO DEVELOPER Nov. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Developed ABN AMRO client library to fetch bank transactions.
- Integrated ABN AMRO into the back office dashboard.

RaboBank Value Chain Viewer

Utrecht. The Netherlands

Rotterdam, The Netherlands

Apr. 2021 - Oct. 2021

PYTHON, FASTAPI DEVELOPER

- Developed Backed API for Value Chain Viewer project using FastAPI.
- · Setup proper dev environment for more efficient development due to high level access control across the bank.

Hack Your Future Amsterdam, The Netherlands

MENTOR AND REACT TEACHER

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2019

• Teacher and mentor helping refugees learn programming and develop their career.

Jump.Work Amsterdam, The Netherlands

CTO Feb. 2016 - Jul. 2017

- Developed entire product stack using Python/Django, Postgresql, Heroku, Redis (Backend) and React/Redux and Nodejs (Frontend).
- · Hired and managed a small team of engineers.
- Trained frelshly graduated developers.

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Developed a distributed web scraper to collect public data and avoid API rate limits.
- Implemented a framework to run a set of phsychometric tests to assess candindates on Jump.Work platform.
- Worked closely with the business/design team to translate the work into actionable sprints.
- Worked closely with external stakeholders on technical challenges and finding solutions.

Ginger Payments Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Developed the credit card payment section of Kassa Compleet
- Developed the Equens workflows for handling direct debit process.
- Refactored the backend improved the code quality and efficiency of the backend API.
- Coordinated with external auditors to ensure compliance.
- Hired severa new software developers to join the team.

Telegraaf Media Groep Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Aug. 2013 - Jun. 2015

Jul. 2015 - Jan. 2016

- Redesign and implemented the Telegraaf Android app.
- Developed parts of the backed for the Telegraaf and the Telesport Andriod apps.
- Developed, optimised and scaled Oranjepoul website for 2014 World Cup predictions.
- Hired several engineers from different countries to join the Telegraaf Media Groep.

West Consulting B.V. Delft, The Netherlands SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul. 2012 - Jul. 2013

· Developed the reporting and visualisation parts of Rijkswaterstaat Interaction Monitor to get reports on highway activities.

• Developed the bidding part of the Bridge game for the uBid Android app.

Vembler Amsterdam, The Netherlands

PYTHON, DJANGO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2012 - May. 2014

• Designed and developed Vembler, an application to help startups reach product market fit.

Amsterdam, The Netherlands & Beonten, Inc.

Boston, USA

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2012 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Remote contribution to Barter development, a knowledge sharing system.

Education

Delft University of Technology

Delft, The Netherlands

M.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2009 - 2012

- · Specialisation in Networks and Distributed Systems
- Thesis: Inferring Private Attributes in Online Social Networks

Skills

Programming Languages Python, Javascript, Java, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Rust, PHP

Framework Django, Flask, FastAPI, Airflow, Hotwire, htmx

Infrustructure AWS, Terraform, Azure, Docker, Heroku, PostgreSQL, InfluxDB, Redis, Elasticsearch, Kubernetes

Languages Persian (Farsi), English, Dutch

Crypto Bitcoin, Lightning and Ethereum fundamentals, Solidity, DeFi, Clarity

Extracurricular Activity

Delft International Student Society (DISS)

Delft, Netherlands

BOARD MEMBER

LINUX TEACHER

2010 - 2011

- Organising student excursions and visits.
- Managing the website and IT of the organsiation.

Amirkabir University of Technology

Tehran, Iran

2008 - 2009

• Teaching linux voluntarily to B.Sc. and M.Sc. students.